堆到底是什么，malloc到底是做什么的？
Those are questions we try to answer in this video.
你可能已经知道，当你在编程时，你需要一些，更多的内存，你可能会使用
the heap, by allocating memory with malloc and if you are done you free it again.
不知怎么的，一些魔法正在发生，你不知道你是如何神奇地得到的。
more memory or give it back.
在我们讨论malloc之前，我们先讨论一下我们的进程如何获得任何内存。
in the first place.
This is done via mmap or brk.
Those are system calls, which means we ask the kernel directly.
mmap请求内核给我们一些新的虚拟地址空间，基本上请求一个新的
memory segment.
除了mmap之外，还有brk，可以用来改变已经使用的
This is real fucking magic.
最后，这个过程并不关心这个内存是如何实现的-如果有RAM，
在RAM上的确切位置存储它，或者如果您有一个交换文件，因为您没有
have enough RAM.
内核和硬件负责处理这个问题，并将内存映射到进程中，
意味着进程可以透明地访问这些内存地址并使用它们
- and transparent in this context means, “doesn’t have to know anything about it”.
您可以使用strace执行heap1，并且可以看到所有对mmap的调用最初设置为
up the processes memory regions.
And near the end it uses brk to setup the heap.
那么，我们为什么不使用mmap或brk为我们的进程获取更多的内存呢？
为什么我们总是用malloc和free谈论堆？
好吧，malloc只是一个非常花哨和方便的包装，可以处理BRK或MMAPping
for us.
And does much more.
Malloc will call mmap or brk to get more memory if the heap doesn’t exist or is too small.
But on top of that it will help us to organize and manage that memory.
同样，在CTF挑战期间，以及我们稍后将看到的示例中，使用堆
so little, that we won’t see any additional memory mapped regions.
为了简单起见，我们认为堆只是一大块固定内存
mapped memory.
And we can do in this memory whatever we want.
So when we refer to the heap, we actually mean this memory region.
那么，malloc将管理堆意味着什么呢？
Let’s explore this abstractly first.
We want to allocate 8 bytes.
So we call malloc with 8.
This means we block 8 bytes on the heap.
对malloc的每个调用都将返回区域被阻塞的堆的地址，以及
with this address we know where we can write our 8 bytes to.
So we can now write the string “AAAABBBB” to that address.
Now we allocate two more times.
malloc(8), malloc(8).
This begs the question what does blocking mean.
Malloc如何知道返回的地址？
如果我雇你给我写一个程序，给我一个我可以使用的内存地址
safely for different sizes, you could come up with a working solution.
And if you would implement that you would have created your own heap algorithm.
So there are many different ways one could implement that.
Though most commonly used is an implementation called DLmalloc.
Because a dude with the name Douglas Lea wrote it.
malloc算法将为它所阻塞的每个块存储块的大小。
before it.
And it will also keep 4 bytes before that empty for how the free is implemented.
But we will only focus on malloc for now.
Let’s do the mallocs again, and let’s think like a computer.
所以在开始的时候，当第一个malloc被调用时，我们显然知道
the heap.
所以我们存储要在那里分配的大小，并返回块所在的地址
part, that is usable by the programmer, starts.
但是，malloc现在如何知道下一个调用malloc的位置
放置？
Not that we write over our previously allocated area.
Well we obviously have to kinda memorize where our free region begins.
所以malloc只需要做一些计算，并更新指向开头的地址
of the heap, by adding the size of the chunk we allocated to it.
And this happens every malloc.
So there is a pointer somewhere, that will always point to free memory.
Cool.
Just for understanding purposes.
考虑到malloc的返回地址，你能怎么处理？
Well, this pointer points to the start where we can write data to.
So if we look at the address just before that, we can read the size of the current chunk.
如果我们知道大小，我们可以将大小添加到该地址以访问下一个块
the heap.
Where we can do the same again.
Now let’s have a look at the heap level 1 challenge from protostar.
We will use that example to look at how malloc works in real-life.
但首先，让我们一行一行地遍历代码，并尝试想象堆将如何
look like.
And then next video we actually do that practically.
The objective here seems to call winner().
So we somehow have to redirect code execution to that function.
在顶部有一个名为internet的结构，它有两个成员，一个优先级
integer.
第二个成员是一个名为name的char指针，也就是说name包含一个指针
to a string somewhere else.
Structs are like classes.
At least in terms of providing a structure with multiple different member attributes.
现在，main从类型struct internet指针定义了三个变量，但只有两个变量
are used.
I guess a leftover from creating this level.
我强调结构Internet指针，因为这三个Internet对象没有存储
on the stack.
Only the addresses, the pointer, to those objects are stored in i1, i2 and i3.
Anyhow, then it starts allocating those objects on the heap.
It first calls malloc with enough space for the i1 object.
Sizeof will return the number of bytes this struct requires.
在本例中是8，因为整数优先级是4个字节和char指针，
which is an address, is also 4 bytes.
Because we are on a 32bit machine.
And we know that malloc returns the address on the heap that we can now use.
So i1 points to the start of 8 bytes in memory.
现在我们要将优先级设置为1，它将1写入分配的
area.
然后它再分配8个字节，结果地址将存储在char中
pointer name.
Which is at offset +4 of the i1 object.
作为一个程序员，我们编写i1-&gt；名称来访问name属性，但是实现了它吗？
在这种情况下，I1+4是
char pointer name.
所以现在i1-&gt；名称将包含一个地址，该地址指向我们
just allocated.
Those 8 bytes are intended to store a list of characters, a string - the name.
Then the same is done over again for i2.
We make space for the struct i2.
We set its priority to 2.
And we allocate another 8 byte for the name string.
So basically we have now two objects allocated on the heap that we can work with.
Next come two strcpys.
我们知道strcpy总是非常可疑，因为没有长度指示，而且
we can potentially write more than we have space.
在这种情况下，Internet名称只分配了8个字节，因此我们可以
over those 8 bytes and really screw up stuff.
Anyhow, the strcpy will copy the first argument to the name of the i1 object.
I1指向I1对象的开始，偏移量+4（即名称）是地址
of the free 8 bytes that were allocated for the string.
所以strcpy将获取存储在那里的地址，并从参数1复制字符串。
location.
And the same thing is happening for the second argument with i2 object.
It will take the address stored at +4 of i2, and attempt to copy there our string.
After that, we will printf and then quit the program.
在下一个视频中，我们将在执行该程序以了解
how the heap looks in real-life and how we can work with it in gdb.
Oh by the way.
I lied.
I said the second word would contain the size of the chunk.
Well it does, but also the lowest bit is used to indicate that the PREVIOUS chunk is used.
Not free.
That becomes more important for the free() algorithm.
Thus in our example those numbers values would all be hex 11.
I just want to put a small disclaimer here at the end.
I simplified the heap and malloc a lot.
例如，我只讲了一个指向自由区的指针，实际上在那里
is obviously way more to this.
如果我们研究剥削的历史，我们现在正在研究更多
than 15 years ago - like 2001-ish.
很多东西都没有改变，概念都是一样的，但是很多东西都没有改变。
is also different.
今天的malloc实现是基于dlmalloc的，但它不是最初的dlmalloc
anymore - now its usually referred to as ptmalloc.
And my goal here is to teach you the fundamentals.
尽管这不是100%正确的，但您现在应该大致了解堆是什么，以及
what to look for and you can transfer this knowledge to any heap implementation.